https://www.fembio.org/english/biography.php/woman/privacy-policy

Privacy Policy
Search:
everywhere
in titles only
Preamble
With the following privacy policy we would like to inform you which types of your personal data (hereinafter also abbreviated as " data") we process for which purposes and in which scope. The privacy statement applies to all processing of personal data carried out by us, both in the context of providing our services and in particular on our websites, in mobile applications and within external online presences, such as our social media profiles (hereinafter collectively referred to as "online services").
The terms used are not gender-specific.
Last Update: 9. January 2020
Table of contents
Preamble
Controller
Overview of processing operations
Legal Bases for the Processing
Security Precautions
Transmission and Disclosure of Personal Data
Data Processing in Third Countries
Use of Cookies
Performing tasks in accordance with statutes or rules of procedure
Blogs and publication media
Contacting us
Provision of online services and web hosting
Newsletter and Broadcast Communication
Onlinemarketing
Affiliate-Programms und Affiliate-Links
Profiles in Social Networks
Plugins and embedded functions and content
Overview of processing operations
The following table summarises the types of data processed, the purposes for which they are processed and the concerned data subjects.
Categories of Processed Data
Inventory data (e.g. names, addresses).
Content data (e.g. text input, photographs, videos).
Contact data (e.g. e-mail, telephone numbers).
Meta/communication data (e.g. device information, IP addresses).
Usage data (e.g. websites visited, interest in content, access times).
Contract data (e.g. contract object, duration, customer category).
Payment Data (e.g. bank details, invoices, payment history).
Categories of Data Subjects
Business and contractual partners.
Prospective customers.
Communication partner (Recipients of e-mails, letters, etc.).
Members.
Users (e.g. website visitors, users of online services).
Purposes of Processing
Affiliate Tracking.
Provision of our online services and usability.
Conversion Tracking.
Direct marketing (e.g. by e-mail or postal).
Feedback (e.g. collecting feedback via online form).
Interest-based and behavioral marketing.
contact requests and communication.
Conversion tracking (Measurement of the effectiveness of marketing activities).
Profiling (Creating user profiles).
Remarketing.
Web Analytics (e.g. access statistics, recognition of returning visitors).
Security measures.
Targeting (e.g. profiling based on interests and behaviour, use of cookies).
Contractual services and support.
Managing and responding to inquiries.
Custom Audiences (Selection of relevant target groups for marketing purposes or other output of content).
Legal Bases for the Processing
In the following we inform you about the legal basis of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), on the basis of which we process personal data. Please note that, in addition to the regulations of the GDPR, the national data protection regulations may apply in your country or in our country of residence or domicile.
Consent (Article 6 (1) (a) GDPR) - The data subject has given consent to the processing of his or her personal data for one or more specific purposes.
Performance of a contract and prior requests (Article 6 (1) (b) GDPR) - Performance of a contract to which the data subject is party or in order to take steps at the request of the data subject prior to entering into a contract.
Pprotection of vital interests (Article 6 (1) (d) GDPR) - Processing is necessary in order to protect the vital interests of the data subject or of another natural person.
Legitimate Interests (Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR) - Processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by the controller or by a third party, except where such interests are overridden by the interests or fundamental rights and freedoms of the data subject which require protection of personal data.
Security Precautions
We take appropriate technical and organisational measures in accordance with the legal requirements, taking into account the state of the art, the costs of implementation and the nature, scope, context and purposes of processing as well as the risk of varying likelihood and severity for the rights and freedoms of natural persons, in order to ensure a level of security appropriate to the risk.
The measures include, in particular, safeguarding the confidentiality, integrity and availability of data by controlling physical and electronic access to the data as well as access to, input, transmission, securing and separation of the data. In addition, we have established procedures to ensure that data subjects' rights are respected, that data is erased, and that we are prepared to respond to data threats rapidly. Furthermore, we take the protection of personal data into account as early as the development or selection of hardware, software and service providers, in accordance with the principle of privacy by design and privacy by default.
Masking of the IP address: If it is possible for us or the storage of the IP address is not necessary, we shorten or have your IP address shortened. When the IP address is shortened, also known as "IP masking", the last octet, i.e. the last two numbers of an IP address, is deleted (the IP address in this context is an identifier individually assigned to an Internet connection by the online access provider). With the shortening of the IP address, the identification of a person on the basis of their IP address is to be prevented or made considerably more difficult.
SSL encryption (https): In order to protect your data transmitted via our online services in the best possible way, we use SSL encryption. You can recognize such encrypted connections by the prefix https:// in the address bar of your browser.
Transmission and Disclosure of Personal Data
In the context of our processing of personal data, it may happen that the data is transferred to other places, companies or persons or that it is disclosed to them. Recipients of this data may include, for example, payment institutions within the context of payment transactions, service providers commissioned with IT tasks or providers of services and content that are embedded in a website. In such a case, the legal requirements will be respected and in particular corresponding contracts or agreements, which serve the protection of your data, will be concluded with the recipients of your data.
Data Processing in Third Countries
If we process data in a third country (i.e. outside the European Union (EU), the European Economic Area (EEA)) or the processing takes place in the context of the use of third party services or disclosure or transfer of data to other persons, bodies or companies, this will only take place in accordance with the legal requirements.
Subject to express consent or transfer required by contract or law, we process or have processed the data only in third countries with a recognised level of data protection, which includes US processors certified under the "Privacy Shield" or on the basis of special guarantees, such as a contractual obligation through so-called standard protection clauses of the EU Commission, the existence of certifications or binding internal data protection regulations (Article 44 to 49 GDPR, information page of the EU Commission: https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/international-dimension-data-protection_en).
Use of Cookies
Cookies are text files that contain data from visited websites or domains and are stored by a browser on the user's computer. A cookie is primarily used to store information about a user during or after his visit within an online service. The information stored can include, for example, the language settings on a website, the login status, a shopping basket or the location where a video was viewed. The term "cookies" also includes other technologies that fulfil the same functions as cookies (e.g. if user information is stored using pseudonymous online identifiers, also referred to as "user IDs").
The following types and functions of cookies are distinguished:
Temporary cookies (also: session cookies): Temporary cookies are deleted at the latest after a user has left an online service and closed his browser.
Permanent cookies: Permanent cookies remain stored even after closing the browser. For example, the login status can be saved or preferred content can be displayed directly when the user visits a website again. The interests of users who are used for range measurement or marketing purposes can also be stored in such a cookie.
First-Party-Cookies: First-Party-Cookies are set by ourselves.
Third party cookies: Third party cookies are mainly used by advertisers (so-called third parties) to process user information.
Necessary (also: essential) cookies: Cookies can be necessary for the operation of a website (e.g. to save logins or other user inputs or for security reasons).
Statistics, marketing and personalisation cookies: Cookies are also generally used to measure a website's reach and when a user's interests or behaviour (e.g. viewing certain content, using functions, etc.) are stored on individual websites in a user profile. Such profiles are used, for example, to display content to users that corresponds to their potential interests. This procedure is also referred to as "tracking", i.e. tracking the potential interests of users. . If we use cookies or "tracking" technologies, we will inform you separately in our privacy policy or in the context of obtaining consent.
Information on legal basis: The legal basis on which we process your personal data with the help of cookies depends on whether we ask you for your consent. If this applies and you consent to the use of cookies, the legal basis for processing your data is your declared consent. Otherwise, the data processed with the help of cookies will be processed on the basis of our legitimate interests (e.g. in a business operation of our online service and its improvement) or, if the use of cookies is necessary to fulfill our contractual obligations.
General information on Withdrawal of consent and objection (Opt-Out): Respective of whether processing is based on consent or legal permission, you have the option at any time to object to the processing of your data using cookie technologies or to revoke consent (collectively referred to as "opt-out"). You can initially explain your objection using the settings of your browser, e.g. by deactivating the use of cookies (which may also restrict the functionality of our online services). An objection to the use of cookies for online marketing purposes can be raised for a large number of services, especially in the case of tracking, via the websites http://www.aboutads.info/choices/ and http://www.youronlinechoices.com. In addition, you can receive further information on objections in the context of the information on the used service providers and cookies.
Processing Cookie Data on the Basis of Consent: Before we process or have processed data within the context of the usage of cookies, we ask the users for their consent, which can be revoked at any time. Before the consent has not been given, we may use cookies that are necessary for the operation of our online services. Their use is based on our interest and the user's interest in the expected functionality of our online services.
Cookie Settings/ Opt-Out:
https://www.fembio.org/biographie.php/frau/cookie-settings
Processed data types: Usage data (e.g. websites visited, interest in content, access times), Meta/communication data (e.g. device information, IP addresses).
Data subjects: Users (e.g. website visitors, users of online services).
Legal Basis: Consent (Article 6 (1) (a) GDPR), Legitimate Interests (Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR).
Performing tasks in accordance with statutes or rules of procedure
We process the data of our members, supporters, prospects, business partners or other persons (collectively, " data subjects ") when we have a membership or other business relationship with them and perform our functions and are recipients of benefits and benefits. Otherwise, we process the data of data subjects on the basis of our legitimate interests, e.g. when it concerns administrative tasks or public relations.
The data processed, the type, scope and purpose and the necessity of their processing, are determined by the underlying membership or contractual relationship, from which the necessity of any data information arises (otherwise we refer to necessary data).
We delete data that is no longer required for the performance of our statutory and business purposes. This is determined according to the respective tasks and contractual relationships. We retain the data for as long as it may be relevant for the purpose of conducting business and with regard to any warranty or liability obligations on the basis of our legitimate interest in their regulation. The necessity of storing the data is checked regularly; otherwise the statutory storage obligations apply.
Processed data types: Inventory data (e.g. names, addresses), Payment Data (e.g. bank details, invoices, payment history), Contact data (e.g. e-mail, telephone numbers), Contract data (e.g. contract object, duration, customer category).
Data subjects: Users (e.g. website visitors, users of online services), Members, Business and contractual partners.
Purposes of Processing: Contractual services and support, contact requests and communication, Managing and responding to inquiries.
Legal Basis: Performance of a contract and prior requests (Article 6 (1) (b) GDPR), Legitimate Interests (Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR).
Blogs and publication media
We use blogos or comparable means of online communication and publication (hereinafter "publication medium"). Readers' data will only be processed for the purposes of the publication medium to the extent necessary for its presentation and communication between authors and readers or for security reasons. For the rest, we refer to the information on the processing of visitors to our publication medium within the scope of this privacy policy.
Comment subscriptions: When users leave comments or other contributions, their IP addresses may be stored based on our legitimate interests. This is done for our safety, if someone leaves illegal contents (insults, forbidden political propaganda, etc.) in comments and contributions. In this case, we ourselves can be prosecuted for the comment or contribution and are therefore interested in the author's identity.
Furthermore, we reserve the right to process user data for the purpose of spam detection on the basis of our legitimate interests.
On the same legal basis, in the case of surveys, we reserve the right to store the IP addresses of users for the duration of the surveys and to use cookies in order to avoid multiple votes.
The personal information provided in the course of comments and contributions, any contact and website information as well as the content information will be stored permanently by us until the user objects.
Gravatar Profile Pictures: We use the service Gravatar within our on-line offer and in particular in the Blog.
Gravatar is a service where users can register and store profile pictures and their e-mail addresses. If users leave contributions or comments with the respective e-mail address on other online presences (especially in blogs), their profile pictures can be displayed next to the contributions or comments. For this purpose, the e-mail address provided by the users is transmitted to Gravatar in encrypted form for the purpose of checking whether a profile is stored for it. This is the only purpose of transmitting the email address and it will not be used for other purposes, but deleted thereafter.
The use of Gravatar is based on our legitimate interests, as we use Gravatar to offer authors of contributions and comments the opportunity to personalize their contributions with a profile picture.
By displaying the images, Gravatar knows the IP address of the user, as this is necessary for communication between a browser and an online service.
If users do not want a user image linked to their e-mail address to appear in the comments at Gravatar, they should use an e-mail address which is not stored at Gravatar for commenting. We would also like to point out that it is also possible to use an anonymous e-mail address or no e-mail address at all if users do not wish their own e-mail address to be sent to Gravatar. Users can completely prevent the transmission of data by not using our comment system.
Processed data types: Inventory data (e.g. names, addresses), Contact data (e.g. e-mail, telephone numbers), Content data (e.g. text input, photographs, videos), Usage data (e.g. websites visited, interest in content, access times), Meta/communication data (e.g. device information, IP addresses).
Data subjects: Users (e.g. website visitors, users of online services).
Purposes of Processing: Contractual services and support, Feedback (e.g. collecting feedback via online form), Security measures, Managing and responding to inquiries.
Legal Basis: Performance of a contract and prior requests (Article 6 (1) (b) GDPR), Legitimate Interests (Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR), Consent (Article 6 (1) (a) GDPR), Pprotection of vital interests (Article 6 (1) (d) GDPR).
Services and service providers being used:
Gravatar Profile Pictures: Profile Pictures; Service provider: Automattic Inc., 60 29th Street #343, San Francisco, CA 94110, USA; Website: https://automattic.com; Privacy Policy: https://automattic.com/privacy.
Contacting us
When contacting us (e.g. by contact form, e-mail, telephone or via social media), the data of the inquiring persons are processed insofar as this is necessary to answer the contact enquiries and any requested activities.
The response to contact enquiries within the framework of contractual or pre-contractual relationships is made in order to fulfil our contractual obligations or to respond to (pre)contractual enquiries and otherwise on the basis of the legitimate interests in responding to the enquiries.
Processed data types: Inventory data (e.g. names, addresses), Contact data (e.g. e-mail, telephone numbers), Content data (e.g. text input, photographs, videos).
Data subjects: Communication partner (Recipients of e-mails, letters, etc.).
Purposes of Processing: contact requests and communication.
Legal Basis: Performance of a contract and prior requests (Article 6 (1) (b) GDPR), Legitimate Interests (Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR).
Provision of online services and web hosting
In order to provide our online services securely and efficiently, we use the services of one or more web hosting providers from whose servers (or servers they manage) the online services can be accessed. For these purposes, we may use infrastructure and platform services, computing capacity, storage space and database services, as well as security and technical maintenance services.
The data processed within the framework of the provision of the hosting services may include all information relating to the users of our online services that is collected in the course of use and communication. This regularly includes the IP address, which is necessary to be able to deliver the contents of online services to browsers, and all entries made within our online services or from websites.
E-mail Sending and Hosting: The web hosting services we use also include sending, receiving and storing e-mails. For these purposes, the addresses of the recipients and senders, as well as other information relating to the sending of e-mails (e.g. the providers involved) and the contents of the respective e-mails are processed. The above data may also be processed for SPAM detection purposes. Please note that e-mails on the Internet are generally not sent in encrypted form. As a rule, e-mails are encrypted during transport, but not on the servers from which they are sent and received (unless a so-called end-to-end encryption method is used). We can therefore accept no responsibility for the transmission path of e-mails between the sender and reception on our server.
Collection of Access Data and Log Files: We, ourselves or our web hosting provider, collect data on the basis of each access to the server (so-called server log files). Server log files may include the address and name of the web pages and files accessed, the date and time of access, data volumes transferred, notification of successful access, browser type and version, the user's operating system, referrer URL (the previously visited page) and, as a general rule, IP addresses and the requesting provider.
The server log files can be used for security purposes, e.g. to avoid overloading the servers (especially in the case of abusive attacks, so-called DDoS attacks) and to ensure the stability and optimal load balancing of the servers .
Processed data types: Content data (e.g. text input, photographs, videos), Usage data (e.g. websites visited, interest in content, access times), Meta/communication data (e.g. device information, IP addresses).
Data subjects: Users (e.g. website visitors, users of online services).
Legal Basis: Legitimate Interests (Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR).
Newsletter and Broadcast Communication
We send newsletters, e-mails and other electronic communications (hereinafter referred to as "newsletters") only with the consent of the recipient or a legal permission. Insofar as the contents of the newsletter are specifically described within the framework of registration, they are decisive for the consent of the user. Otherwise, our newsletters contain information about our services and us.
In order to subscribe to our newsletters, it is generally sufficient to enter your e-mail address. We may, however, ask you to provide a name for the purpose of contacting you personally in the newsletter or to provide further information if this is required for the purposes of the newsletter.
Double opt-in procedure: The registration to our newsletter takes place in general in a so-called Double-Opt-In procedure. This means that you will receive an e-mail after registration asking you to confirm your registration. This confirmation is necessary so that no one can register with external e-mail addresses.
The registrations for the newsletter are logged in order to be able to prove the registration process according to the legal requirements. This includes storing the login and confirmation times as well as the IP address. Likewise the changes of your data stored with the dispatch service provider are logged.
Deletion and restriction of processing: We may store the unsubscribed email addresses for up to three years based on our legitimate interests before deleting them to provide evidence of prior consent. The processing of these data is limited to the purpose of a possible defense against claims. An individual deletion request is possible at any time, provided that the former existence of a consent is confirmed at the same time. In the case of an obligation to permanently observe an objection, we reserve the right to store the e-mail address solely for this purpose in a blacklist.
Information on legal bases: The sending of the newsletter is based on the consent of the recipients or, if consent is not required, on the basis of our legitimate interests in direct marketing. Insofar as we engage a service provider for sending e-mails, this is done on the basis of our legitimate interests. The registration procedure is recorded on the basis of our legitimate interests for the purpose of demonstrating that it has been conducted in accordance with the law.
Contents: News on fembio.org, commentaries, specials.
Processed data types: Inventory data (e.g. names, addresses), Contact data (e.g. e-mail, telephone numbers), Meta/communication data (e.g. device information, IP addresses).
Data subjects: Communication partner (Recipients of e-mails, letters, etc.).
Purposes of Processing: Direct marketing (e.g. by e-mail or postal).
Legal Basis: Consent (Article 6 (1) (a) GDPR), Legitimate Interests (Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR).
Opt-Out: You can cancel the receipt of our newsletter at any time, i.e. revoke your consent or object to further receipt. You will find a link to cancel the newsletter either at the end of each newsletter or you can otherwise use one of the contact options listed above, preferably e-mail.
Onlinemarketing
We process personal data for the purposes of online marketing, which may include in particular the marketing of advertising space or the display of advertising and other content (collectively referred to as "Content") based on the potential interests of users and the measurement of their effectiveness.
For these purposes, so-called user profiles are created and stored in a file (so-called "cookie") or similar procedure in which the relevant user information for the display of the aforementioned content is stored. This information may include, for example, content viewed, websites visited, online networks used, communication partners and technical information such as the browser used, computer system used and information on usage times. If users have consented to the collection of their sideline data, these can also be processed.
The IP addresses of the users are also stored. However, we use provided IP masking procedures (i.e. pseudonymisation by shortening the IP address) to ensure the protection of the user's by using a pseudonym. In general, within the framework of the online marketing process, no clear user data (such as e-mail addresses or names) is secured, but pseudonyms. This means that we, as well as the providers of online marketing procedures, do not know the actual identity of the users, but only the information stored in their profiles.
The information in the profiles is usually stored in the cookies or similar memorizing procedures. These cookies can later, generally also on other websites that use the same online marketing technology, be read and analyzed for purposes of content display, as well as supplemented with other data and stored on the server of the online marketing technology provider.
Exceptionally, clear data can be assigned to the profiles. This is the case, for example, if the users are members of a social network whose online marketing technology we use and the network links the profiles of the users in the aforementioned data. Please note that users may enter into additional agreements with the social network providers or other service providers, e.g. by consenting as part of a registration process.
As a matter of principle, we only gain access to summarised information about the performance of our advertisements. However, within the framework of so-called conversion measurement, we can check which of our online marketing processes have led to a so-called conversion, i.e. to the conclusion of a contract with us. The conversion measurement is used alone for the performance analysis of our marketing activities.
Unless otherwise stated, we kindly ask you to consider that cookies used will be stored for a period of two years.
Information on legal basis: If we ask users for their consent (e.g. in the context of a so-called "cookie banner consent"), the legal basis for processing data for online marketing purposes is this consent. Otherwise, user data will be processed on the basis of our legitimate interests (i.e. interest in the analysis, optimisation and economic operation of our online services. In this context, we would also like to refer you to the information on the use of cookies in this privacy policy.
Processed data types: Usage data (e.g. websites visited, interest in content, access times), Meta/communication data (e.g. device information, IP addresses).
Data subjects: Users (e.g. website visitors, users of online services), Prospective customers.
Purposes of Processing: Targeting (e.g. profiling based on interests and behaviour, use of cookies), Remarketing, Conversion Tracking, Interest-based and behavioral marketing, Profiling (Creating user profiles), Conversion tracking (Measurement of the effectiveness of marketing activities), Web Analytics (e.g. access statistics, recognition of returning visitors), Custom Audiences (Selection of relevant target groups for marketing purposes or other output of content).
Security measures: IP Masking (Pseudonymization of the IP address).
Legal Basis: Consent (Article 6 (1) (a) GDPR), Legitimate Interests (Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR).
Opt-Out: We refer to the privacy policies of the respective service providers and the possibilities for objection (so-called "opt-out"). If no explicit opt-out option has been specified, it is possible to deactivate cookies in the settings of your browser. However, this may restrict the functions of our online offer. We therefore recommend the following additional opt-out options, which are offered collectively for each area: a) Europe: https://www.youronlinechoices.eu. b) Canada: https://www.youradchoices.ca/choices. c) USA: https://www.aboutads.info/choices. d) Cross-regional: http://optout.aboutads.info.
Services and service providers being used:
Google Analytics: Online marketing and web analytics; Service provider: Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland, parent company: Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA; Website: https://marketingplatform.google.com/intl/en/about/analytics/; Privacy Policy: https://policies.google.com/privacy; Privacy Shield (Safeguarding the level of data protection when processing data in the USA): https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active; Opt-Out: Opt-Out-Plugin: http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en, Settings for the Display of Advertisements: https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated.
Amazon: Marketing of advertising media and advertising spaces; Service provider: Amazon Europe Core S.à.r.l., Amazon EU S.à.r.l., Amazon Services Europe S.à.r.l. and Amazon Media EU S.à.r.l., all four located at 38, avenue John F. Kennedy, L-1855 Luxembourg, and Amazon Instant Video Germany GmbH, Domagkstr. 28, 80807 Munich (together \"Amazon Europe\"), parent company: Amazon.com, Inc., 2021 Seventh Ave, Seattle, Washington 98121, USA; Website: https://www.amazon.com; Privacy Policy: https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=201909010; Privacy Shield (Safeguarding the level of data protection when processing data in the USA): https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TOWQAA4&status=Active.
Affiliate-Programms und Affiliate-Links
Within our online services, we include so-called affiliate links or other references (which for example may include discount codes) to the offers and services of third parties (collectively referred to as "affiliate links"). When users follow affiliate links or subsequently take advantage of offers, we may receive commission or other benefits (collectively referred to as "commission") from these third parties.
In order to be able to track whether the users have followed the offers of an affiliate link used by us, it is necessary for the respective third party to know that the users have followed an affiliate link used within our online services. The assignment of affiliate links to the respective business transactions or other actions (e.g., purchases) serves the sole purpose of commission settlement and is removed as soon as it is no longer required for this purpose.
For the purposes of the aforementioned affiliate link assignment, the affiliate links may be supplemented by certain values that may be a component of the link or otherwise stored, for example, in a cookie. The values may include in particular the source website (referrer), time, an online identifier of the operator of the website on which the affiliate link was located, an online identifier of the respective offer, the type of link used, the type of offer and an online identifier of the user.
Information on legal basis: If we ask the users for their consent to the use of third party providers, the legal basis of the processing is consent. Furthermore, the processing can be a component of our (pre)contractual services, provided that the use of the third party was agreed within this context. Otherwise, user data will be processed on the basis of our legitimate interests (i.e. interest in efficient, economic and recipient friendly services). In this context, we would also like to refer you to the information on the use of cookies in this privacy policy.
Processed data types: Contract data (e.g. contract object, duration, customer category), Usage data (e.g. websites visited, interest in content, access times), Meta/communication data (e.g. device information, IP addresses).
Data subjects: Users (e.g. website visitors, users of online services).
Purposes of Processing: Affiliate Tracking.
Legal Basis: Consent (Article 6 (1) (a) GDPR), Performance of a contract and prior requests (Article 6 (1) (b) GDPR), Legitimate Interests (Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR).
Services and service providers being used:
Amazon Affiliate Program: Amazon Affiliate Program - Amazon and the Amazon logo are trademarks of Amazon.com, Inc. or one of its affiliates. Service provider: Amazon Europe Core S.à.r.l., Amazon EU S.à.r.l., Amazon Services Europe S.à.r.l. and Amazon Media EU S.à.r.l., all four located at 38, avenue John F. Kennedy, L-1855 Luxembourg, and Amazon Instant Video Germany GmbH, Domagkstr. 28, 80807 Munich (together "Amazon Europe"), parent company: Amazon.com, Inc., 2021 Seventh Ave, Seattle, Washington 98121, USA.; Website: https://www.amazon.com; Privacy Policy: https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=201909010; Privacy Shield (Safeguarding the level of data protection when processing data in the USA): https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TOWQAA4&status=Active.
Profiles in Social Networks
We maintain online presences within social networks in order to communicate with the users active there or to offer ind information about us there.
We would like to point out that user data may be processed outside the European Union. This may entail risks for users, e.g. by making it more difficult to enforce users' rights. With regard to US providers certified under the Privacy Shield or offering comparable guarantees of a secure level of data protection, we would like to point out that they thereby commit themselves to comply with EU data protection standards.
In addition, user data is usually processed within social networks for market research and advertising purposes. For example, user profiles can be created on the basis of user behaviour and the associated interests of users. The user profiles can then be used, for example, to place advertisements within and outside the networks which are presumed to correspond to the interests of the users. For these purposes, cookies are usually stored on the user's computer, in which the user's usage behaviour and interests are stored. Furthermore, data can be stored in the user profiles independently of the devices used by the users (especially if the users are members of the respective networs or will become members later on).
For a detailed description of the respective processing operations and the opt-out options, please refer to the respective data protection declarations and information provided by the providers of the respective networks.
Also in the case of requests for information and the exercise of rights of data subjects, we point out that these can be most effectively pursued with the providers. Only the providers have access to the data of the users and can directly take appropriate measures and provide information. If you still need help, please do not hesitate to contact us.
Processed data types: Inventory data (e.g. names, addresses), Contact data (e.g. e-mail, telephone numbers), Content data (e.g. text input, photographs, videos), Usage data (e.g. websites visited, interest in content, access times), Meta/communication data (e.g. device information, IP addresses).
Data subjects: Users (e.g. website visitors, users of online services).
Purposes of Processing: contact requests and communication, Targeting (e.g. profiling based on interests and behaviour, use of cookies), Remarketing, Web Analytics (e.g. access statistics, recognition of returning visitors).
Legal Basis: Legitimate Interests (Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR).
Services and service providers being used:
Facebook: Social network; Service provider: Facebook Ireland Ltd., 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2, Irland, parent company: Facebook, 1 Hacker Way, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA; Website: https://www.facebook.com; Privacy Policy: https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy; Privacy Shield (Safeguarding the level of data protection when processing data in the USA): https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnywAAC&status=Active; Opt-Out: Settings for advertisements: https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=ads; Additional information on data protection: Agreement on the joint controll of processing of personal data on Facebook pages: https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms/page_controller_addendum, privacy policy for Facebook pages: https://www.facebook.com/legal/terms/information_about_page_insights_data.
Plugins and embedded functions and content
Within our online services, we integrate functional and content elements that are obtained from the servers of their respective providers (hereinafter referred to as "third-party providers"). These may, for example, be graphics, videos or social media buttons as well as contributions (hereinafter uniformly referred to as "Content").
The integration always presupposes that the third-party providers of this content process the IP address of the user, since they could not send the content to their browser without the IP address. The IP address is therefore required for the presentation of these contents or functions. We strive to use only those contents, whose respective offerers use the IP address only for the distribution of the contents. Third parties may also use so-called pixel tags (invisible graphics, also known as "web beacons") for statistical or marketing purposes. The "pixel tags" can be used to evaluate information such as visitor traffic on the pages of this website. The pseudonymous information may also be stored in cookies on the user's device and may include technical information about the browser and operating system, referring websites, visit times and other information about the use of our website, as well as may be linked to such information from other sources.
Information on legal basis: If we ask users for their consent (e.g. in the context of a so-called "cookie banner consent"), the legal basis for processing is this consent. Otherwise, user data will be processed on the basis of our legitimate interests (i.e. interest in the analysis, optimisation and economic operation of our online services. We refer you to the note on the use of cookies in this privacy policy.
Processed data types: Usage data (e.g. websites visited, interest in content, access times), Meta/communication data (e.g. device information, IP addresses), Contact data (e.g. e-mail, telephone numbers), Content data (e.g. text input, photographs, videos), Inventory data (e.g. names, addresses).
Data subjects: Users (e.g. website visitors, users of online services), Communication partner (Recipients of e-mails, letters, etc.).
Purposes of Processing: Provision of our online services and usability, Targeting (e.g. profiling based on interests and behaviour, use of cookies), Feedback (e.g. collecting feedback via online form), Contractual services and support, Security measures, Managing and responding to inquiries, contact requests and communication, Direct marketing (e.g. by e-mail or postal), Interest-based and behavioral marketing, Profiling (Creating user profiles).
Legal Basis: Consent (Article 6 (1) (a) GDPR), Legitimate Interests (Article 6 (1) (f) GDPR), Performance of a contract and prior requests (Article 6 (1) (b) GDPR).
Services and service providers being used:
Shariff: We use the privacy-secure "Shariff" buttons. "Shariff" was developed to provide more privacy on the net and to replace the usual "share" buttons of social networks. It is not the browser of the user, but the server on which this online offer is located, which establishes a connection with the server of the respective social media platforms and queries, for example, the number of Likes, etc.. The user remains anonymous. More information about the Shariff project can be found at the developers of the magazine c't: https://www.heise.de/ct/artikel/Shariff-Social-Media-Buttons-mit-Datenschutz-2467514.html. Service provider: Heise Medien GmbH & Co. KG, Karl-Wiechert-Allee 10, 30625 Hannover, Germany; Website: https://www.heise.de/ct/artikel/Shariff-Social-Media-Buttons-mit-Datenschutz-2467514.html; Privacy Policy: https://www.heise.de/Datenschutzerklaerung-der-Heise-Medien-GmbH-Co-KG-4860.html.
YouTube: Service provider: Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland, , parent company: Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA; Website: https://www.youtube.com; Privacy Policy: https://policies.google.com/privacy; Privacy Shield (Safeguarding the level of data protection when processing data in the USA): https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active; Opt-Out: Opt-Out-Plugin: http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en, Settings for the Display of Advertisements: https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated.
Vimeo: Video platform; Service provider: Vimeo Inc., Attention: Legal Department, 555 West 18th Street New York, New York 10011, USA; Website: https://vimeo.com; Privacy Policy: https://vimeo.com/privacy; Opt-Out: We point out that Vimeo may use Google Analytics and refer to the privacy policy (https://policies.google.com/privacy) as well as opt-out options for Google Analytics (http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en) or the settings of Google for data use for marketing purposes (https://adssettings.google.com/).
Erasure of data
The data processed by us will be erased in accordance with the statutory provisions as soon as their processing is revoked or other permissions no longer apply (e.g. if the purpose of processing this data no longer applies or they are not required for the purpose).
If the data is not deleted because they are required for other and legally permissible purposes, their processing is limited to these purposes. This means that the data will be restricted and not processed for other purposes. This applies, for example, to data that must be stored for commercial or tax reasons or for which storage is necessary to assert, exercise or defend legal claims or to protect the rights of another natural or legal person.
Further information on the erasure of personal data can also be found in the individual data protection notices of this privacy policy.
Changes and Updates to the Privacy Policy
We kindly ask you to inform yourself regularly about the contents of our data protection declaration. We will adjust the privacy policy as changes in our data processing practices make this necessary. We will inform you as soon as the changes require your cooperation (e.g. consent) or other individual notification.
If we provide addresses and contact information of companies and organizations in this privacy policy, we ask you to note that addresses may change over time and to verify the information before contacting us.
Rights of Data Subjects
As data subject, you are entitled to various rights under the GDPR, which arise in particular from Articles 15 to 18 and 21 of the GDPR:
Right to Object: You have the right, on grounds arising from your particular situation, to object at any time to the processing of your personal data which is based on letter (e) or (f) of Article 6(1) GDPR , including profiling based on those provisions.
Where personal data are processed for direct marketing purposes, you have the right to object at any time to the processing of the personal data concerning you for the purpose of such marketing, which includes profiling to the extent that it is related to such direct marketing.
Right of withdrawal for consents: You have the right to revoke consents at any time.
Right of access: You have the right to request confirmation as to whether the data in question will be processed and to be informed of this data and to receive further information and a copy of the data in accordance with the provisions of the law.
Right to rectification: You have the right, in accordance with the law, to request the completion of the data concerning you or the rectification of the incorrect data concerning you.
Right to Erasure and Right to Restriction of Processing: In accordance with the statutory provisions, you have the right to demand that the relevant data be erased immediately or, alternatively, to demand that the processing of the data be restricted in accordance with the statutory provisions.
Right to data portability: You have the right to receive data concerning you which you have provided to us in a structured, common and machine-readable format in accordance with the legal requirements, or to request its transmission to another controller.
Complaint to the supervisory authority: You also have the right, under the conditions laid down by law, to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, in particular in the Member State of your habitual residence, place of work or place of the alleged infringement if you consider that the processing of personal data relating to you infringes the GDPR.
Terminology and Definitions
This section provides an overview of the terms used in this privacy policy. Many of the terms are drawn from the law and defined mainly in Article 4 GDPR. The legal definitions are binding. The following explanations, on the other hand, are intended above all for the purpose of comprehension. The terms are sorted alphabetically.
Affiliate Tracking: Affiliate tracking logs links that the linking websites use to refer users to websites with products or other offers. The owners of the respective linked websites can receive a commission if users follow these so-called "affiliate links" and subsequently take advantage of the offers (e.g. buy goods or use services). To this end, it is necessary for providers to be able to track whether users who are interested in certain offers subsequently follow the affiliate links. It is therefore necessary for the functionality of affiliate links that they are supplemented by certain values that become part of the link or are otherwise stored, e.g. in a cookie. The values include in particular the source website (referrer), time, an online identification of the owner of the website on which the affiliate link was located, an online identification of the respective offer, an online identifier of the user, as well as tracking specific values such as advertising media ID, partner ID and categorizations.
Controller: "Controller" means the natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which, alone or jointly with others, determines the purposes and means of the processing of personal data.
Conversion Tracking: "Conversion Tracking" refers to a procedure by which the effectiveness of marketing measures can be determined. As a rule, a cookie is stored on the devices of the users within the websites on which the marketing measures are carried out and then called up again on the target website (e.g. this enables us to track whether the ads we placed on other websites were successful).
Conversion tracking: Conversion tracking is a method used to evaluate the effectiveness of marketing measures. For this purpose, a cookie is usually stored on the devices of the users within the websites on which the marketing measures take place and then called up again on the target website (e.g. we can thus trace whether the advertisements placed by us on other websites were successful).
Custom Audiences: Target group formation (or "custom audiences") is the term used when target groups are determined for advertising purposes, e.g. display of advertisements. For example, a user's interest in certain products or topics on the Internet may be used to infer that that user is interested in advertisements for similar products or the online store in which they viewed the products. Lookalike Audiences" (or similar target groups) is the term used to describe content that is viewed as suitable by users whose profiles or interests presumably correspond to the users for whom the profiles were created. Cookies are generally used for the purposes of creating custom audiences and lookalike audiences. Target groups can be created by processing visitors of an online service or can be uploaded to the provider of an online marketing technology by means of uploading (which is usually done pseudonymised).
IP Masking: IP masking is a method by which the last octet, i.e. the last two numbers of an IP address, are deleted so that the IP address alone can no longer be used to uniquely identify a person. IP masking is therefore a means of pseudonymising processing methods, particularly in online marketing.
Interest-based and behavioral marketing: Interest-related and/or behaviour-related marketing is the term used when potential user interest in advertisements and other content is predicted if possible. This is done on the basis of information on the previous behaviour of users (e.g. visiting and staying on certain websites, purchasing behaviour or interaction with other users), which is stored in a so-called profile. For these purposes cookies are usually used.
Personal Data: "personal data" means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person ("data subject"); an identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person.
Processing: The term "processing" covers a wide range and practically every handling of data, be it collection, evaluation, storage, transmission or erasure.
Profiling: "Profiling" means any automated processing of personal data consisting in the use of such personal data to analyse, evaluate or predict certain personal aspects relating to a natural person (depending on the type of profiling, this includes information regarding age, gender, location and movement data, interaction with websites and their contents, shopping behaviour, social interactions with other people) (e.g. interests in certain contents or products, click behaviour on a website or the location). Cookies and web beacons are often used for profiling purposes.
Remarketing: Remarketing" or "retargeting" is the term used, for example, to indicate for advertising purposes which products a user is interested in on a website in order to remind the user of these products on other websites, e.g. in advertisements.
Targeting: Tracking" is the term used when the behaviour of users can be traced across several websites. As a rule, behavior and interest information with regard to the websites used is stored in cookies or on the servers of the tracking technology providers (so-called profiling). This information can then be used, for example, to display advertisements to users presumably corresponding to their interests.
Web Analytics: Web Analytics serves the evaluation of visitor traffic of online services and can determine their behavior or interests in certain information, such as content of websites. With the help of web analytics, website owners, for example, can recognize at what time visitors visit their website and what content they are interested in. This allows them, for example, to optimize the content of the website to better meet the needs of their visitors. For purposes of web analytics, pseudonymous cookies and web beacons are frequently used in order to recognise returning visitors and thus obtain more precise analyses of the use of an online service.
Werbung
backto top
Cookie-Einstellungen
On our webiste we make use of cookies. Some of which are essential while others help us to improve our services and generate revenue to cover our costs. You may accept this by clicking the button
Accept all cookies & close or you may configure your desired personal settings. You may change these settings at any given time by clicking the 'cookie-settings'-link located at the footer of the website. Further information can be found in our privacy policy.
Below there is an overview of all cookies used on this website. You may allow or decline any category. By clicking on 'Details' you can show more detailed information about each cookie.
Essential cookies
Essential cookies enable basic functions and are necessary for the website to function properly.
Details
Name:
exp_visitor_consents
Anbieter:
Fembio
Host(s):
fembio.org
Zweck:
Saves responses to Consent requests for non-logged in visitors
Expiration:
{cookie_info:expiration}
Name:
exp_csrf_token
Anbieter:
Fembio
Host(s):
fembio.org
Zweck:
A security cookie used to identify the user and prevent Cross Site Request Forgery attacks.
Expiration:
{cookie_info:expiration}
Name:
exp_last_activity
Anbieter:
Fembio
Host(s):
fembio.org
Zweck:
Records the time of the last page load. Used in conjunction with the last_visit cookie.
Expiration:
{cookie_info:expiration}
Name:
exp_last_visit
Anbieter:
Fembio
Host(s):
fembio.org
Zweck:
Date of the user’s last visit.
Expiration:
{cookie_info:expiration}
Name:
srp
Anbieter:
VG Wort
Host(s):
*.met.vgwort.de
Zweck:
The VG Wort cookie helps determine the likelihood of our texts being copied and ensures that authors and publishers are compensated for legal claims. IP addresses are only processed in anonymous form.
Privacy policy:
https://www.vgwort.de/datenschutz.html
Expiration:
{cookie_info:expiration}
Name:
PHPSESSID
Anbieter:
Fembio
Host(s):
fembio.org
Zweck:
Preserves users states across page requests.
Expiration:
{cookie_info:expiration}
YouTube videos
Some videos on our website include YouTube videos. For this a 2-click solution is used, which means that no data is sent to YouTube before you decide to start playback by clicking on the preview.
The videos are then integrated using YouTube's extended data protection mode. By clicking on the play button, you give your consent for YouTube to set cookies on the device you are using, which can also be used to analyze usage behavior for market research and marketing purposes. You can find more information on the use of cookies by YouTube in Google's cookie policy at https://policies.google.com/technologies/types?hl=en.
Details
Name:
NID
Provider:
Google
Host(s):
.google.com
Purpose:
The NID cookie contains a unique ID Google uses to remember your preferences and other information, such as your preferred language (e.g. English), how many search results you wish to have shown per page (e.g. 10 or 20), and whether or not you wish to have Google’s SafeSearch filter turned on.
Privacy policy:
https://policies.google.com/technologies/types
Expiration:
6 monts
Name:
CONSENT
Provider:
Google
Host(s):
.google.com
Purpose:
Stores the information on whether the user has agreed to Google's privacy policy.
Privacy policy:
https://policies.google.com/technologies/types
Expiration:
until 2038
Name:
1P_JAR
Provider:
Google
Host(s):
.google.com
Purpose:
These cookies are used for the purpose of targeted advertising.
Privacy policy:
https://policies.google.com/technologies/types
Expiration:
30 days
Name:
ANID
Provider:
Google
Host(s):
.google.com
Purpose:
These cookies are used for the purpose of targeted advertising.
Privacy policy:
https://policies.google.com/technologies/types
Expiration:
76 days
Name:
DV
Provider:
Google
Host(s):
.google.com
Purpose:
These cookies are used for the purpose of targeted advertising.
Privacy policy:
https://policies.google.com/technologies/types
Expiration:
browser session
Functionality cookies
These cookies help us personalize content and functionality for you, including remembering changes you have made to parts of the website that you can customize, or selections for services made on previous visits. If you do not allow these cookies, some portions of our website may be less friendly and easy to use, forcing you to enter content or set your preferences on each visit.
Details
Name:
exp_tracker
Provider:
Fembio
Host(s):
fembio.org
Purpose:
Contains the last 5 pages viewed, encrypted for security. Typically used for form or error message returns.
Expiration:
browser session
Name:
exp_save_info
Provider:
Fembio
Host(s):
fembio,org
Purpose:
If set to ‘yes’, allows additional cookies to store guest user information for use when filling out comment forms. This cookie is only set if you submit a comment.
Expiration:
1 year
Name:
exp_my_name
Provider:
Fembio
Host(s):
fembio.org
Purpose:
Name specified when posting a comment and you chose to save your info.
Expiration:
1 year
Name:
exp_my_email
Provider:
Fembio
Host(s):
fembio.org
Purpose:
Email address specified when posting a comment and you chose to save your info.
Expiration:
1 year
Statistics cookies
These cookies allow us measure how visitors use our website, which pages are popular, and what our traffic sources are. This helps us improve how our website works and make it easier for all visitors to find what they are looking for. The information is aggregated and anonymous, and cannot be used to identify you. If you do not allow these cookies, we will be unable to use your visits to our website to help make improvements.
Details
Name:
_gat_*
Provider:
Google LLC
Host(s):
fembio.org
Purpose:
Used by Google Analytics to throttle request rate
Privacy policy:
https://policies.google.com/privacy
Expiration:
1 day
Name:
_ga
Provider:
Google LLC
Host(s):
fembio.org
Purpose:
Registers a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data on how the visitor uses the website.
Privacy policy:
https://policies.google.com/privacy
Expiration:
2 years
Name:
_gid
Provider:
Google LLC
Host(s):
fembio.org
Purpose:
Registers a unique ID that is used to generate statistical data on how the visitor uses the website.
Privacy policy:
https://policies.google.com/privacy
Expiration:
1 day
Marketing cookies
These cookies are usually placed by third-party advertising networks, which may use information about your website visits to develop a profile of your interests. This information may be shared with other advertisers and/or websites to deliver more relevant advertising to you across multiple websites. If you do not allow these cookies, visits to this website will not be shared with advertising partners and will not contribute to targeted advertising on other websites.
Details
Name:
ad-id
Provider:
Amazon
Host(s):
amazon-adsystem.com
Purpose:
Is set by the external Amazon service for advertisements.
Details about the Amazon cookies and their deactivation: Amazon-Cookies
Privacy policy:
https://www.amazon.de/gp/help/customer/display.html?ie=UTF8&nodeId=201909010&ref_=footer_privacy
Expiration:
200 days
Name:
ad-privacy
Provider:
Amazon
Host(s):
amazon-adsystem.com
Purpose:
Is set by the external Amazon service for advertisements.
Details about the Amazon cookies and their deactivation: Amazon-Cookies
Privacy policy:
https://www.amazon.de/gp/help/customer/display.html?ie=UTF8&nodeId=201909010&ref_=footer_privacy
Expiration:
5 years
Name:
ad-pref-session
Provider:
Amazon
Host(s):
amazon-adsystem.com
Purpose:
Is set by the external Amazon service for advertisements.
Details about the Amazon cookies and their deactivation: Amazon-Cookies
Privacy policy:
https://www.amazon.de/gp/help/customer/display.html?ie=UTF8&nodeId=201909010&ref_=footer_privacy
Expiration:
browser session
Name:
affili_0
Provider:
Awin
Host(s):
.webmasterplan.com
Purpose:
Used to notify Affilinet's system of a creative view.
Privacy policy:
https://www.awin.com/de/datenschutzerklarung
Expiration:
30 days
Name:
affili_{progid}
Provider:
Awin
Host(s):
.webmasterplan.com
Purpose:
Used to notify Affilinet's system of a creative view.
Privacy policy:
https://www.awin.com/de/datenschutzerklarung
Expiration:
30 days
Save settings
